- type: Basic
  tags: [Standard]
  fields:
    Front: 'A'
    Back: 'Separable assembly or sub-assembly (e.g. printed circuit assembly)'

- type: Basic
  tags: [Standard]
  fields:
    Front: 'AE'
    Back: 'Aerial, antenna'

- type: Basic
  tags: [Unofficial]
  fields:
    Front: 'ASSY'
    Back: 'Separable assembly'

- type: Basic
  tags: [Standard]
  fields:
    Front: 'AT'
    Back: 'Attenuator or isolator'

- type: Basic
  tags: [Unofficial]
  fields:
    Front: 'B'
    Back: 'Battery'

- type: Basic
  tags: [Standard]
  fields:
    Front: 'BR'
    Back: 'Bridge rectifier (four diodes in a package). Often changed to "D" for diode'

- type: Basic
  tags: [Standard]
  fields:
    Front: 'BT'
    Back: 'Battery. Often shortened to "B".'

- type: Basic
  tags: [Standard]
  fields:
    Front: 'C'
    Back: 'Capacitor'

- type: Basic
  tags: [Standard]
  fields:
    Front: 'CB'
    Back: 'Circuit Breaker'

- type: Basic
  tags: [Unofficial]
  fields:
    Front: 'CN'
    Back: 'Connector'

- type: Basic
  tags: [Standard]
  fields:
    Front: 'CN'
    Back: 'Capacitor network. May be simplified to "C" for capacitor'

- type: Basic
  tags: [Unofficial]
  fields:
    Front: 'CRT'
    Back: 'Cathode ray tube'

- type: Basic
  tags: [Standard]
  fields:
    Front: 'D, CR'
    Back: 'Diode (all types, including LED), thyristor. "D" is preferred for various types of diodes'

- type: Basic
  tags: [Standard]
  fields:
    Front: 'DL'
    Back: 'Delay line'

- type: Basic
  tags: [Standard]
  fields:
    Front: 'DS'
    Back: 'Display, general light source, lamp, signal light'

- type: Basic
  tags: [Unofficial]
  fields:
    Front: 'DSP'
    Back: 'Digital signal processor'

- type: Basic
  tags: [Standard]
  fields:
    Front: 'F'
    Back: 'Fuse'

- type: Basic
  tags: [Standard]
  fields:
    Front: 'FB'
    Back: 'Ferrite bead. Sometimes changed to "L" for inductor, though "E" was used in the currently inactive standard IEEE 315 (see Clause 22.4).'

- type: Basic
  tags: [Standard]
  fields:
    Front: 'FD'
    Back: 'Fiducial'

- type: Basic
  tags: [Unofficial]
  fields:
    Front: 'FET'
    Back: 'Field-effect transistor'

- type: Basic
  tags: [Standard]
  fields:
    Front: 'FL'
    Back: 'Filter'

- type: Basic
  tags: [Standard]
  fields:
    Front: 'G'
    Back: 'Generator or oscillator'

- type: Basic
  tags: [Unofficial]
  fields:
    Front: 'GDT, SVP'
    Back: 'Gas discharge tube, surge voltage protector'

- type: Basic
  tags: [Standard]
  fields:
    Front: 'GL'
    Back: 'Graphical logo'

- type: Basic
  tags: [Standard]
  fields:
    Front: 'GN'
    Back: 'General network'

- type: Basic
  tags: [Unofficial]
  fields:
    Front: 'H'
    Back: 'Pin header'

- type: Basic
  tags: [Standard]
  fields:
    Front: 'H'
    Back: 'Hardware, e.g., screws, nuts, washers. Sometimes hardware is expanded to "HW"'

- type: Basic
  tags: [Standard]
  fields:
    Front: 'HY'
    Back: 'Circulator or directional coupler'

- type: Basic
  tags: [Standard]
  fields:
    Front: 'IR'
    Back: 'Infrared diode; often changed to "D" for diode'

- type: Basic
  tags: [Standard]
  fields:
    Front: 'J'
    Back: 'Jack (least-movable connector of a connector pair), jack connector (connector may have "male" pin contacts and/or "female" socket contacts). All types of connectors, including pin headers.'

- type: Basic
  tags: [Unofficial]
  fields:
    Front: 'J, JW'
    Back: 'Wire link ("jumper")'

- type: Basic
  tags: [Unofficial]
  fields:
    Front: 'JFET'
    Back: 'Junction gate field-effect transistor'

- type: Basic
  tags: [Standard]
  fields:
    Front: 'JP'
    Back: 'Jumper (link)'

- type: Basic
  tags: [Standard]
  fields:
    Front: 'K'
    Back: 'Relay or contactor'

- type: Basic
  tags: [Standard]
  fields:
    Front: 'L'
    Back: 'Inductor or coil or ferrite bead'

- type: Basic
  tags: [Unofficial]
  fields:
    Front: 'LA'
    Back: 'Lightning arrester'

- type: Basic
  tags: [Unofficial]
  fields:
    Front: 'LCD'
    Back: 'Liquid crystal display'

- type: Basic
  tags: [Unofficial]
  fields:
    Front: 'LDR'
    Back: 'Light-dependent resistor'

- type: Basic
  tags: [Unofficial]
  fields:
    Front: 'LED'
    Back: 'Light-emitting diode'

- type: Basic
  tags: [Standard]
  fields:
    Front: 'LS'
    Back: 'Loudspeaker or buzzer'

- type: Basic
  tags: [Standard]
  fields:
    Front: 'M'
    Back: 'Motor'

- type: Basic
  tags: [Unofficial]
  fields:
    Front: 'MCB'
    Back: 'Miniature circuit breaker'

- type: Basic
  tags: [Unofficial]
  fields:
    Front: 'MIC'
    Back: 'Microphone'

- type: Basic
  tags: [Standard]
  fields:
    Front: 'MK'
    Back: 'Microphone'

- type: Basic
  tags: [Unofficial]
  fields:
    Front: 'MOSFET'
    Back: 'Metal-oxide-semiconductor field-effect transistor'

- type: Basic
  tags: [Unofficial]
  fields:
    Front: 'MOV'
    Back: 'Metal-oxide varistor'

- type: Basic
  tags: [Standard]
  fields:
    Front: 'MP'
    Back: 'Mechanical part (including screws and fasteners)'

- type: Basic
  tags: [Unofficial]
  fields:
    Front: 'NE'
    Back: 'Neon lamp'

- type: Basic
  tags: [Standard]
  fields:
    Front: 'OP'
    Back: 'Opto-isolator; often changed to "U" for IC'

- type: Basic
  tags: [Standard]
  fields:
    Front: 'P'
    Back: 'Plug (most-movable connector of a connector pair), plug connector (connector may have "male" pin contacts and/or "female" socket contacts)'

- type: Basic
  tags: [Unofficial]
  fields:
    Front: 'PCB'
    Back: 'Printed circuit board'

- type: Basic
  tags: [Unofficial]
  fields:
    Front: 'PLC'
    Back: 'Programmable logic controller'

- type: Basic
  tags: [Standard]
  fields:
    Front: 'PS'
    Back: 'Power supply'

- type: Basic
  tags: [Unofficial]
  fields:
    Front: 'PU'
    Back: 'Pickup'

- type: Basic
  tags: [Standard]
  fields:
    Front: 'Q'
    Back: 'Transistor (all types)'

- type: Basic
  tags: [Standard]
  fields:
    Front: 'R'
    Back: 'Resistor'

- type: Basic
  tags: [Standard]
  fields:
    Front: 'RN'
    Back: 'Resistor network; sometimes simplified to "R" for resistor, or "N" for network'

- type: Basic
  tags: [Standard]
  fields:
    Front: 'RT'
    Back: 'Thermistor; sometimes simplified to "R" for resistor'

- type: Basic
  tags: [Standard]
  fields:
    Front: 'RV'
    Back: 'Varistor, variable resistor'

- type: Basic
  tags: [Unofficial]
  fields:
    Front: 'RY, RLA'
    Back: 'Relay'

- type: Basic
  tags: [Standard]
  fields:
    Front: 'S'
    Back: 'Switch (all types, including buttons)'

- type: Basic
  tags: [Standard]
  fields:
    Front: 'SA'
    Back: 'Spark Arrester'

- type: Basic
  tags: [Unofficial]
  fields:
    Front: 'SCR'
    Back: 'Silicon-controlled rectifier'

- type: Basic
  tags: [Unofficial]
  fields:
    Front: 'SUS'
    Back: 'Silicon unilateral switch'

- type: Basic
  tags: [Unofficial]
  fields:
    Front: 'SW'
    Back: 'Switch'

- type: Basic
  tags: [Standard]
  fields:
    Front: 'T'
    Back: 'Transformer; sometimes changed to "L" for inductor'

- type: Basic
  tags: [Standard]
  fields:
    Front: 'TC'
    Back: 'Thermocouple'

- type: Basic
  tags: [Unofficial]
  fields:
    Front: 'TFT'
    Back: 'Thin-film transistor (display)'

- type: Basic
  tags: [Unofficial]
  fields:
    Front: 'TH'
    Back: 'Thermistor'

- type: Basic
  tags: [Standard]
  fields:
    Front: 'TP'
    Back: 'Test point'

- type: Basic
  tags: [Standard]
  fields:
    Front: 'TUN'
    Back: 'Tuner'

- type: Basic
  tags: [Standard]
  fields:
    Front: 'U, IC'
    Back: 'Integrated circuit (IC); shorter "U" (unit) is preferred instead of "IC"'

- type: Basic
  tags: [Standard]
  fields:
    Front: 'V'
    Back: 'Vacuum tube'

- type: Basic
  tags: [Unofficial]
  fields:
    Front: 'VC'
    Back: 'Variable capacitor'

- type: Basic
  tags: [Unofficial]
  fields:
    Front: 'VDR'
    Back: 'Voltage-dependent resistor'

- type: Basic
  tags: [Unofficial]
  fields:
    Front: 'VFD'
    Back: 'Vacuum fluorescent display'

- type: Basic
  tags: [Standard]
  fields:
    Front: 'VR'
    Back: 'Voltage regulator (voltage reference), or variable resistor (potentiometer / trimmer / rheostat). Voltage regulators are often "U" for IC, pots and trimmers often "R" for resistor'

- type: Basic
  tags: [Unofficial]
  fields:
    Front: 'VT'
    Back: 'Voltage transformer'

- type: Basic
  tags: [Unofficial]
  fields:
    Front: 'W'
    Back: 'Wire'

- type: Basic
  tags: [Standard]
  fields:
    Front: 'X'
    Back: 'Socket connector for another item not P or J, paired with the letter symbol for that item (XV for vacuum tube socket, XF for fuse holder, XA for printed circuit assembly connector, XU for integrated circuit connector, XDS for light socket, etc.)'

- type: Basic
  tags: [Standard]
  fields:
    Front: 'X, XTAL, Y'
    Back: 'Crystal, ceramic resonator, powered oscillator'
